<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.0.1/eml.xsd" packageId="8a9e9bff-8f96-4e3d-aaf4-d50e1da3d2a3" system="http://symbiota.org" scope="system" xml:lang="eng"><dataset><title xml:lang="eng">SCAN general data extract</title><creator id="2f57806a-f37f-40b2-915b-6fcdf6ae100f"><organizationName>SCAN</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>Neil.Cobb@nau.edu</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/index.php</onlineUrl></creator><metadataProvider><organizationName>SCAN</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>Neil.Cobb@nau.edu</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/index.php</onlineUrl></metadataProvider><pubDate>2021-05-28</pubDate><language>eng</language><associatedParty><organizationName>Museum of Comparative Zoology, Harvard University</organizationName><individualName>bdim@oeb.harvard.edu</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>bdim@oeb.harvard.edu</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>The Albert J. Cook Arthropod Research Collection</organizationName><individualName>Anthony Cognato</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>cognato@msu.edu</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>Essig Museum of Entomology</organizationName><individualName>Peter Oboyski</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>essig.museum@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>Illinois Natural History Survey Insect Collection</organizationName><individualName>Tommy McElrath</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>monotomidae@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>iNaturalist Research-grade Observations</organizationName><individualName>Ken-ichi Ueda</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>kueda@inaturalist.org</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>Native Bee Inventory and Monitoring Lab - US-CA-MX - Bees</organizationName><individualName>Sam Droege</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>sdroege@usgs.gov</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>Bee Biology and Systematics Laboratory</organizationName><individualName>Terry Griswold</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>Terry.Griswold@ars.usda.gov</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>The Centre for Biodiversity Genomics - University of Guelph</organizationName><individualName>Dr. Jeremy deWaard</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>dewaardj@uoguelph.ca</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>University of Guelph Insect Collection (DEBU)</organizationName><individualName>Steven Paiero</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>paieros@uoguelph.ca</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>University of New Hampshire Collection of Insects and Arthropods (UNHC-UNHC)</organizationName><individualName>Istvan Miko</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>istvan.miko@gmail.com</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty><associatedParty><organizationName>AMNH Arthropods</organizationName><individualName>Christine Johnson</individualName><positionName>Collection Manager</positionName><role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role><electronicMailAddress>cjohnson@AMNH.ORG</electronicMailAddress><phone></phone></associatedParty></dataset><additionalMetadata><metadata><symbiota><dateStamp>2021-05-28T06:10:20-07:00</dateStamp><citation identifier="92e808c1-c2f0-46a2-9a5f-119651324b41">SCAN - 92e808c1-c2f0-46a2-9a5f-119651324b41</citation><physical><characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding><dataFormat><externallyDefinedFormat><formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName></externallyDefinedFormat></dataFormat></physical><collection identifier="029816b2-ba46-4c89-9ebb-c1c630a0ce7e" id="19"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=19</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>MCZ</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>Museum of Comparative Zoology, Harvard University</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>http://scan-bugs.org/portal/images/collicons/fh.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://mcz.harvard.edu/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>President and Fellows of Harvard College</additionalInfo><abstract><para>The Museum of Comparative Zoology was founded in 1859 on the concept that collections are an integral and fundamental component of zoological research and teaching. This more than 150-year-old commitment remains a strong and proud tradition for the MCZ. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; The present-day MCZ contains over 21-million specimens in ten research collections which comprise one of the world's richest and most varied resources for studying the diversity of life. The museum serves as the primary repository for zoological specimens collected by past and present Harvard faculty-curators, staff and associates conducting research around the world. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt; As a premier university museum and research institution, the specimens and their related data are available to researchers of the scientific and museum community.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="15cdb244-b82d-4798-af5e-ef7bc138f233" id="76"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=76</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>MSU</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>MSUC</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>The Albert J. Cook Arthropod Research Collection</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>http://scan-bugs.org/portal/images/collicons/msu.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://www.arc.ent.msu.edu/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>Department of Entomology, MSU</additionalInfo><abstract><para>In 1867, Professor Albert J. Cook started the ARC and it currently houses ~ 1.5 million specimens mounted on pins, slides or stored in alcohol representing ~35,000 species. A significant portion of the collection represents the insect diversity Michigan and the Great Lakes Region. Other significant collections represent the world-wide arthropod fauna for select taxa, e.g., Lepidoptera and Scolytinae. Researchers in systematics, agriculture, natural resources, urban insect management, to extension personnel and to the general public use these specimens. Please direct inquiries to Anthony Cognato, Director or Gary Parsons, Manager (parsonsg@cns.msu.edu).</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="80d44c88-540b-464a-8d68-e5c996a0af73" id="90"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=90</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>EMEC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>EMEC</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>Essig Museum of Entomology</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>http://scan-bugs.org/portal/images/collicons/essig.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://essig.berkeley.edu</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>Regents of the University of California</additionalInfo><abstract><para>The Essig Museum of Entomology maintains ca. six million pinned, slide-mounted, and fluid preserved specimens of terrestrial and fresh water arthropods with a focus on western North America, particularly California. Other well-represented regions include Costa Rica, Chile, Australia, New Caledonia, Hawaii, and French Polynesia. The collection was formalized in 1939 with the launch of the California Insect Survey, although some specimens date back to the 1890’s. New accessions continue to add to our holdings through faculty, staff, and student research, and generous donations from insect enthusiasts and other collectors. The Essig Museum is part of the Berkeley Natural History Museum consortium.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="d93d943b-2390-4e2c-9050-11a9ec9a2a96" id="100"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=100</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>INHS</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>INHSIC</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>Illinois Natural History Survey Insect Collection</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>http://scan-bugs.org/portal/content/collicon/inhs-inhsic.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://insect.inhs.illinois.edu/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</intellectualRights><abstract><para>The insect collection at the Survey now houses over 7,000,000 curated specimens. The growth and wide-ranging scope of this collection can be credited to the diverse interests of the systematists who have spent all or part of their career at the Survey. Scientists such as Stephen A. Forbes, the first Director of the State Laboratory and Chief of the Natural History Survey; Theodore Frison, who succeeded Forbes; and H. H. Ross, who directed the intense systematics studies of the faunistic section for 40 years, placed considerable emphasis on enlarging the insect collection. These insects document the changing landscape and environmental conditions of the world. The INHS insect collection is one of the largest in North America. The most recent size estimate was done in 1992. The heavy concentration of specimens from the last third of the 1800s also makes this one of North America's oldest insect and related arthropod collections. The INHS Insect Collection includes more than 13,000 primary types (syntypes inclusive). Because of size, historical holdings, and wide breadth of coverage in certain groups, the collection is an important national and worldwide resource.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="c280e822-464b-4689-b5c5-a2bdf12b894e" id="103"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=103</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>iNaturalist</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>Observations</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>iNaturalist Research-grade Observations</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>http://scan-bugs.org/portal/images/collicons/inat-bird-logo.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://www.inaturalist.org</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>Rights for individual observations belong to the individual observers. In jurisdictions where collections of data are are considered intellectual property, the rights holder of this collection is the California Academy of Sciences.</additionalInfo><abstract><para>iNaturalist.org is a website where anyone can record their observations from nature. Members record observations for numerous reasons, including participation in citizen science projects, class projects, and personal fulfillment.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="95067882-e084-4028-a6ae-fe1e045a4992" id="111"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=111</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>USGS</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>PWRC-US-CA-MX</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>Native Bee Inventory and Monitoring Lab - US-CA-MX - Bees</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/content/collicon/usgs-pwrc-us-ca-mx.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><abstract><para>Species occurrence records for native and non-native bees, wasps and other insects collected using mainly pan, malaise, and vane trapping; and insect netting methods in Canada, Mexico, the non-contiguous United States, U.S. Territories (specifically U.S. Virgin Islands), and U.S. Minor Outlying Islands. Some records also contain notes regarding plants or substrates from which insects were collected or that were present and/or in flower at the time the insects were collected. Unless otherwise noted, taxonomic determinations (identifications) were completed by Sam Droege (USGS Patuxent Wildlife Research Center - PWRC).</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="b870b19f-b0ea-4d3c-b3f0-53fbaf062e0c" id="122"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=122</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>USDA</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>ARS</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>Bee Biology and Systematics Laboratory</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>http://scan-bugs.org/portal/content/collicon/usda-ars.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://www.ars.usda.gov/pacific-west-area/logan-ut/pollinating-insect-biology-management-systematics-research/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><abstract><para>This is a one-time snapshot collection of data originally hosted by GBIF: http://www.gbif.org/publisher/1e26a630-7203-11dc-a0d8-b8a03c50a862 &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The Pollinating Insects -- Biology, Management and Systematics Research Unit (PIRU) was founded in the late 1940s as part of the alfalfa seed production unit. We focus primarily on pollination research with bees.The mission of the Pollinating Insect - Biology, Management and Systematics Research Unit is the development of non-Apis bees, for example the alfalfa leafcutting bee and blue orchard bee, as crop pollinators. Research emphasis areas include the development and improvement of management systems for bee populations, biological studies of bees, plant-pollination systems, and bee biosystematics. Cross-pollinated crops not effectively pollinated by honey bees have been targeted for improved pollination management, and the candidacy of selected pollinator species continues to be evaluated. Current research on established species, like the alfalfa leafcutting bee and blue orchard bee, is directed toward developing control programs for pests and diseases, improving management that will result in better bee health and demonstrating pollination efficacy and increased producer profitability on "new" crops.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="ee581109-9559-4332-b6b6-1d3ea904b5fb" id="135"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=135</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>University of Guelph, Centre for Biodiversity</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>BIOUG</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>The Centre for Biodiversity Genomics - University of Guelph</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/content/collicon/university_of_guelph,_centre_f.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>http://biodiversitygenomics.net/units/collections/</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><abstract><para>The Centre for Biodiversity Genomics (CBG) archive at the University of Guelph currently holds over 2.8 million voucher specimens (as of March 2017). Every specimen is digitized, and the exact storage location of each specimen is tracked in a collection management information system for quick reference and retrieval. The databased information for every voucher is also archived in the Barcode of Life Data System (BOLD), permitting the permanent storage, validation and analysis of barcode sequence data and associated specimen metadata. Nearly 90% of the specimens have been DNA barcoded, and a few representatives of every species have been digitally imaged. The majority of these specimens (roughly 60%) derive from Canada, stemming primarily from collections made by the CBG at 159 sites since 2008 including national parks, provincial parks and other protected or private areas. The collection is taxonomically diverse, spanning 25 phyla, 62 classes, and 263 orders. Employing the Barcode Index Number system as a proxy for species, the collection contains about 175,000 species. Just over 1 million specimens from the collection are included in this resource, which includes all CBG collection events from 2008-2015 at National Parks, National Park Reserves, and National Urban Parks within Canada. All included specimen records are associated with DNA barcode information, and have a link to their associated specimen page on the BOLD. All barcode sequences associated with these specimens have been submitted to GenBank and their accessions are provided in this resource. This data resource is served by the Integrated Publishing Toolkit of Canadensys at http://data.canadensys.net/ipt/resource?r=bioug-specimens. This "snapshot" collection is technically a curated dataset of specimen information from local database and the Barcode of Life Data System (BOLD).</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="fb636c67-ba21-401e-b37f-f0fcbd150fd0" id="242"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=242</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>DEBU</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>ENT</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>University of Guelph Insect Collection (DEBU)</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/content/collicon/debu-ent.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://data.canadensys.net/ipt/resource?r=debu-specimens</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>University of Guelph</additionalInfo><abstract><para>This dataset is provided by Canadensys https://data.canadensys.net/ipt/resource?r=debu-specimens, please go there to obtain raw data. University of Guelph Insect Collection (DEBU) from University of Guelph. http://dx.doi.org/10.5886/4pp2vt5a (accessed on [date]) The University of Guelph Insect Collection has its roots in the insect collection of the Entomological Society of Ontario, founded in 1863. It is the oldest insect collection in Canada and was, in effect, Canada's national insect collection before there was a Canada and before the establishment of the Canadian National Collection in Ottawa. Although our current collection of just over two million specimens is relatively small by world standards, the University of Guelph Insect Collection remains one of North America's most important heritage insect collections, and is Canada's third or fourth largest insect collection. It is the best collection of Ontario insects, including many irreplaceable specimens of extirpated species.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="a7ccda69-f66b-4cf6-b224-3da67d765aa5" id="248"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=248</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>UNHC</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier>UNHC</collectionIdentifier><collectionName>University of New Hampshire Collection of Insects and Arthropods (UNHC-UNHC)</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/content/collicon/unhc-unhc.png</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl>https://unhcollection.unh.edu/database/index.php</onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>University of New Hampshire</additionalInfo><abstract><para>With more than 700,000 specimens and growing, the UNHC is the largest arthropod depository and research collection in northern New England. Over 12,000 species are represented from different regions of New England, featuring many specimens collected from the White Mountains. The UNHC is part of the Department of Biological Sciences and the College of Life Sciences and Agriculture and is dedicated to preserving the rich historical information encompassed by the collection and committed to acquiring new specimens and resources useful to the UNH Department of Biological Sciences and greater scientific community.</para></abstract></collection><collection identifier="66acc5ec-da39-42c7-811a-824c25f96161" id="274"><alternateIdentifier>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=274</alternateIdentifier><parentCollectionIdentifier>AMNH</parentCollectionIdentifier><collectionIdentifier></collectionIdentifier><collectionName>AMNH Arthropods</collectionName><resourceLogoUrl>https://scan-bugs.org:443/portal/content/collicon/amnh.jpg</resourceLogoUrl><onlineUrl></onlineUrl><intellectualRights>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</intellectualRights><additionalInfo>AMNH</additionalInfo><abstract><para>The American Museum of Natural History is the second-largest arthropod collection in the United States with over 18 million specimens and lots.</para></abstract></collection></symbiota></metadata></additionalMetadata></eml:eml>
